>> Jem Young: 我在这里指的是什么箭头 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: What's this arrow
that I'm pointing to here?
有人能告诉我那是什么吗
Can anybody tell me what that is?
嗯。
Yes.
>> 扬声器 2: 这是响应代码吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's the response code?
>> Jem Young: 是的，这是一个状态码。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, it's a status code.
而地位码是我们理所当然要做的事
And status codes are another thing
that we take for granted, but
我们可能知道其中的一些
we probably know some of them.
有人知道任何有趣的状态码吗
Does anybody know any funny status codes?
>> 演讲者 3: 我喜欢 HTTP 状态猫， 405。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I like the HTTP status cats,
the 405.
>> Jem Young: 这些都不错。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Those are pretty good.
外面有很多类似的状态码
There's a lot of like status
code memes out there.
是吗 ?
Yeah?
>> 演讲者 2: 我是茶壶。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I am a teapot.
> > Jem Young: 是的，这是一个好的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, that one's a good one.
状态码 418.
Status code 418.
我喜欢这个
I love that one.
这不是什么意思
It doesn't mean anything.
但它确实存在而且它是官方标准的一部分。
But it exists and
it's part of the official standard.
这背后可能有个有趣的故事
There's probably a funny story behind it.
但我不知道是什么
But I don't know what it is.
>> 扬声器 2: 增强您的冷静。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Enhance your calm.
>> Jem Young: Hm?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Hm?
>> 扬声器 2: 增强您的冷静， 420。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Enhance your calm, 420.
>> Jem Young: 这是实际的状态码吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Is that
an actual status code?
> 演讲者 2: 这是一个推特，是的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's a Twitter one, yeah.
>> Jem Young: [LAUGH] 如果您有自己的状态码，我想人们可以组成自己的状态码。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: [LAUGH] I guess people can
make up their own status code if you have
足够的影响力了 我不知道我不知道
enough clout.
I don't know.
>> 扬声器 2: 我听到 [COUGH] 有一个 IoT 设备茶壶，用于返回茶壶
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I heard [COUGH] there's an
IoT device teapot that returns the teapot
实际上是密码
code now actually.
>> Jem Young: 现在你可以为所欲为
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: You can do whatever
you want now with the status,
那就太好了
that would be a good one.
事实上，我们应该这样做。
Actually, we should do that.
>> 扬声器 2: 我认为它存在。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I think it exists.
[ LAUGH] >> Jem Young: 也许我们会
[LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Maybe we'll make
就是这样做的
an exercise that does that.
你坚持这个想法
You hold that thought.
>> [LAUGH] >> Jem Young: 让我们谈谈
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Let's talk a little bit
关于状态码的信息。
about status code.
状态码将指示 HTTP 请求的状态。
What a status code does is it indicates
the status of the HTTP request.
因为如果你提出请求和回应
Because there if you make a request and
response,
就会有回应的
there's always going
to be a response back.
但在没有状态码的情况下，您不知道该如何处理该响应。
But you don't know what to do with
that response without the status code.
例如，状态码 401 表示您无权使用。
For instance, a status code of
401 means you're not authorized.
这通常意味着您尚未登录。
That generally means you're not logged in.
但真正的状态码就是帮助 Web 应用程序
But really what a status code does
is it helps the web application in
浏览器知道如何处理该响应。
the browser know what to
do with that response.
因为没有这些状态码，它就像，一切都还好。
Because without all of these status codes,
it would just be like, everything's okay.
没事的没事的
Everything's okay.
但是一个 401 的浏览器能够专门处理，甚至更好。
But a 401 the browser can handle
specifically and even better,
您的应用程序可以专门处理。
your application can handle specifically.
404是什么意思
So what's a 404?
我是说我们一直说 404 页
I mean, we say 404 page all the time.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
>> 扬声器 3: 找不到。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Not found.
>> 扬声器 2: 找不到。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Not found.
>> Jem Young: 找不到。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Not found, exactly.
因此，所有这些前缀，所以 1， 2， 3， 4， 5，都是非常具体的。
And so all these prefixes, so the 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, all mean something very specific.
1 ，以 1 开头的任何内容都只是一个信息。
1, anything starting with
a 1 is just an information.
你不想再这么做了
There's not much you wanna do with it.
例如，状态码 101 意味着继续。
For example,
status code 101 just means continue.
这意味着可能有更多的数据即将到来，仅能保持每秒的数据。
It means there's probably more data
coming, and just hold on for a second.
200s 意味着成功。
200s means success.
因此，不同类型的 200s 表示它成功取决于它是什么。
So different types of 200s mean it was
successful depending on what it is.
如此普遍的成功，就像一份漂亮的工作，这个反应是有效的，是 200。
So general success, like nice job,
this response is valid, is 200.
如果这个帖子成功的话，应该是 201，或者
If the post was successful,
it'd be something like 201, or
就像这样
something like that.
依依依时
And so on and so forth.
您不需要了解每个状态码，但了解什么
You don't really need to know every single
status code, but it's good to know what
这些前缀就意味着你马上就知道发生了什么
these prefixes mean, so
you know immediately what's going on.
我们讨论的 3 个问题， 301 个永久移动， 302 个临时重定向。
The threes we talked about, 301 moved
permanently, 302 temporary redirects.
300 个状态码始终重定向。
300 status codes are always redirects.
400 是某种客户机错误。
The 400 are some sort of client error.
所以说你做错了事就像你发出了格式不正确的要求一样
So it means you did something wrong,
as in you've sent a malformed request,
你根本没记错
you weren't logged in correctly.
您正在尝试请求一个不存在的页面，因此是 404 页面。
You're trying to request a page
that doesn't exist, so a 404 page.
这些都是客户机错误。
Those are always client errors.
如果你看到 404 ，那就意味着你做错了什么。
So if you see a 404,
that means you did something wrong.
如果您看到 500 ，这意味着服务器上的错误。
If you see a 500, that means
something on the server's wrong.
500s 是你不想去的
500s are the ones you don't wanna get.
因为你永远不应该回到 500 人的状态
Because you should never be in
a state where you're returning 500s,
因为这意味着你的申请要么不好要么就是路不好
because that means either your
application is bad or the route's bad, or
服务器就在火灾的某个地方
the server is on fire somewhere.
但这意味着存在服务器错误，我们不知道如何处理。
But it just means there's a server error
and we didn't know how to handle it.
服务器应该始终处理自己的错误和
And servers should always
handle their own errors and
然后将其他内容返回给客户机。
then return something else to the client.
怎么了
Yes?
> > 演讲者 2: 我要说，如果你是一个前人，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I was gonna say,
if you're a front ender,
那其实 500 是个很好的答案因为你知道你没弄坏
then actually 500 is a good answer because
you know that you didn't break it.
你知道从理论上来说这是别人的问题
You know that it's somebody else's
problem to deal with, theoretically.
>> Jem Young: 这一点不错。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: That's a good point.
500 是别人的问题
500 is someone else's problem.
400 你的问题
400, your problem.
你这么想吧
Think of it that way.
但这些只是作为网络开发者的好事情，我们可能不知道
But these are just good things to know
as web developers that we probably don't
认为这些东西对他们有意义
think that these things
have meanings to them.
但他们都是什么意思
But they all mean something.
例如， Amazon 具有的内容，如着名的 404 状态页面。
For instance, what does Amazon have,
like a famous 404 status page.
他们就像亚马逊狗一样
You know, they have like Amazon dogs,
当您尝试请求错误路径时，人员会使用 404s 来执行这些操作。
people do fun things with 404s
when you try to request bad paths.
如果你想的话，我们可以写我们的客户申请，而不是
And if you wanted to, we can write our
client application so that instead of
查看服务器错误，这是一件坏事，尤其是如果有人付钱给你
seeing a server error, which is a bad
thing, especially if someone's paying you
你要回来 500s 就意味着你做错事了
money and you're returning 500s,
that means you're doing something wrong.
你可以在客户那边处理然后说我要 500 了就像
You can handle that on the client side and
say like, I'm getting 500, just be like,
出什么事了
hey, something went wrong.
我们现在正在努力，而不是像这张丑陋的 500 页一样。
We're working on right now,
rather than just like that ugly 500 page.
所以了解如何阅读和处理状态码非常好。
So it's good to know how to read and
handle status codes.
所以只需要一个简单的测验
So just a quick quiz.
成功 POST 请求的正确状态码是什么 ?
What's the proper status code for
a successful POST request?
>> 扬声器 2: 200。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: 200.
>> 演讲者 3: 创建或。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Created, or.
>> Jem Young: 是的， 200 个作品。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, 200 works.
这就意味着，好吧。
That just means, okay.
或者， 201 表示已创建，表示已成功创建。
Or 201 means created,
it means successfully created.
太棒了
Nice.
现在你可以进入了
Now you kind of get in.
就像你在这个层次开始思考的时候，你就开始想那种
It's like when you start thinking at this
level, you start thinking about that kind
关于如何构造应用程序的高级工程师的想法
of senior engineer thinking about how
to structure your application and
而不是盲目接受和返回状态码之类的。
not just blindly accept and
return status codes, things like that.
因此，让我们在创建定制标题和定制状态码时进行练习。
So let's do an exercise where we create
a custom header and a custom status code.
所以在你的应用程序中，我们昨天创建的应用程序应该已启动并正在运行，
So in your app, that app we created
yesterday which should be up and running,
创建返回 418的路径，即我是茶壶和定制标题。
create a path that returns 418, which
is I'm a teapot, and a custom header.
请记住，定制头以 X 开头。
And remember, custom headers start with X.
>> Jem Young: 如果你看不出真正的小，就会有一个提示。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: There's a hint at the bottom
if you can't see in really small.
在请求上设置状态码， res.status。
To set a status code on the request,
res.status.
这才是你的责任
That's the response.status.
要设置标题，请重新设置。
To set a header, res.set.